#### Contact

kyra.nankivell@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/kyranank (LinkedIn)

# Top Skills

Web Development REST APIs GPT-4

## Languages

French (Limited Working)

### Certifications

**DELF B1** 

The Complete 2021 Web
Development Bootcamp (65.5h)
Respect in Sport for Activity Leaders
DELF B2

Node with React: Fullstack Web Development (26h)

#### Honors-Awards

Dean's Honours List

Edward L. Donegan Scholarship in Engineering

**UofT Trailblazing Student** 

Ontario Professional Engineers Foundation for Education Undergraduate Scholarship

# Kyra Nankivell

Account Manager @ Toronto Sceptres | Data, Dev & Analytics Toronto, Ontario, Canada

# Summary

At 17, Kyra faced a tough decision: pursue NCAA hockey or follow her passion for technology. With no clear path to a professional career in women's hockey, she chose engineering, earning a full scholarship to the University of Toronto. When the PWHL launched six years later, Kyra saw the chance to merge her love for hockey with her technical skills.

Now part of the Toronto Sceptres ticketing team, she connects fans to the game. But her ambitions reach further—Kyra aims to revolutionize sports with her Al and machine learning skills, setting a new standard with women's sports at the forefront. Outside of work, she volunteers with Black Girl Hockey Club, leading its digital strategy while working to create more opportunities for young women in hockey.

# Experience

Toronto Sceptres
Account Manager
September 2024 - Present (10 months)
Toronto, Ontario, Canada

- Ticket Sales System: Created the first centralized system to track sales across 14 categories of ticket inventory, shared it across 6 markets, and custom-built a tool upon request of another team.
- Customer Data Analysis: Enabled targeted marketing by processing 23,560 lines of customer data to produce new data visualizations including interactive heatmaps overlaid on geographic maps.
- Depositor Gift Distribution: Implemented a cost-effective, data-driven strategy to distribute 100+ outstanding gifts to customers across Ontario, reducing logistical inefficiencies and costs.
- Season Ticket Member (STM) Gift Pickup: Designed a data-validated tracking tool to monitor progress, minimize errors and maintain clear communication with management.

- Salesforce Integration: Contributed with testing and feedback, prompted league-wide documentation, suggested a new workflow and earned direct praise from senior leadership.
- Ticket Management Strategy: Regularly managed ticket release strategy to maximize revenue and maintain necessary holds. Proposed a ticket redistribution solution to increase seat utilization and lower drop rates while increasing alignment with community goals.
- Suite Sales: Improved sales efficiency by encoding a map of suite inventory.
   Identified the limiting factor in suite sales and proposed a solution (now actioned).
- Battle On Bay Street: Manipulated unreliable data to identify STMs who
  had not selected seats for Scotiabank Arena through the primary process.
   Assigned and transferred 328 tickets to 113 accounts while minimizing errors
  to only 6 tickets and allowed for quick management of ticket releases.
- Annual STM Event: Organized an event for over 1,200 participants with multiple activities, including sign design, which became a sponsored activation at every home game across 3 markets.
- Youth Clinics: Led and engaged 136 youth participants with activities, earning recognition from senior leaders for leadership and group engagement.

Prestige Experiential Marketing Inc.

**Brand Ambassador** 

December 2022 - September 2024 (1 year 10 months)

- NBA All-Star Weeknd Salt Lake City, Utah (December 2022)
- Hamilton Watches x Indian Jones Distillery District, Toronto (July 2023)
- Cashmere at the National Bank Open Sobey's Stadium, North York (August 2023)
- Blackberry by CBC Gem The Eaton Centre, Toronto (November 2023)
- LEGO DreamZzz The Toronto Zoo, Scarborough (August/September 2024)

Algorithmics Global Franchise Owner June 2023 - May 2024 (1 year) Toronto, Ontario, Canada

Algorithmics is an international programming school for children aged 6 to 18. Our students learn popular programming languages, take on the role of indemand IT specialists, shoot high-quality content for YouTube/TikTok, and build a portfolio of design projects.

Started in 2016, Algorithmics has grown to 90+ countries with over 1,100,000+ graduates from New York to Singapore. We stand for high-quality education and gamification. Our curriculum was developed by 30 professional teachers with PhDs and international experience in modern technology projects.

Algorithmics Don Valley West is the Toronto location!

RBC Capital Markets
Digital Product Developer
September 2022 - April 2023 (8 months)
Toronto, Ontario, Canada

Worked on the Digital Strategy & Client Insights (DSCi), Digital Platform team to develop RBC's Multi-Asset Trade Platform (MATA) product for internal and external institutional clients.

- Developed the product-market fit (PMF) strategy for MATA including metrics (growth, retention, engagement) and methods to derive insights from each result identified during the process.
- Created an Event Dictionary to capture user actions (clicks, hovers, etc.)
   needed to calculate the metrics outlined in the PMF strategy, collaborated with the development team to refine the implementation specifications and continually updated the document as MATA changed.
- Wrote the MATA Usage Reporting codebase in Python which connected to MongoDB, manipulated data to calculate statistics, formatted tables and graphs with HTML and sent a daily email to management highlighting user usage on MATA. Created detailed documentation and educated others.
- Designed the MATA User Manual following the core user journey with screenshots, feature descriptions, explanations and links to further information.
   Wrote all the content based on multiple sources of information and updated the document every day as MATA changed.

#### YouTube

**Content Creator** 

September 2019 - March 2023 (3 years 7 months)

- Identified a shortage of accurate, relevant, and engaging content regarding the Canadian Armed Forces (CAF) while undergoing the recruitment process in 2019
- Published a video outlining the enrollment process aimed at potential recruits which accumulated 29,339 views, 227 comments and 1,120 likes

- Initiated 34.5% commission deal with Army-Test.com (training software for the entrance exam) and created a video series using their practice materials resulting in \$13,055 USD in revenue to date
- Requested interviews from current CAF members to produce "Exploring the CAF" series (6 episodes and counting) which has a total of 39,994 YouTube views and 2,050 podcast downloads
- Created a Facebook Group (January 3rd 2022) to create a sense of community which has grown to 343 members, 305 active members (89%) and a highly engaged 4-person administrative team
- \*\* Data accurate as of March 30th 2023

#### Hiverlab

Web Development Intern January 2022 - June 2022 (6 months)

Singapore, Singapore

- Developed, tested and automated 5 Python scripts to query and write API data to Hiverlab's central database to drive business insights
- Implemented 3 features in JavaScript for SpatialPlanner web-based product
- Refactored (responsiveness & styling) 5 webpages embedded in a CloudExpo project
- Setup hardware (e.g. computer, camera, trigger) independently for on-site client testing
- Recorded a 250-word voiceover for a virtual educational tour
- Completed a Three.js course to improve SpatialWork product
   For more on Hiverlab, visit www.hiverlab.com

#### **CPP Investments**

Intern Analyst (Equity Trading Desk) May 2021 - August 2021 (4 months)

Toronto, Ontario, Canada

- Worked on the Equity Trading Desk in Financing, Collateral & Trading
- Trained in Excel, VBA, Python, Market Fundamentals
- Wrote and distributed daily updates derived from market analysis
- Developed R Shiny tool to display current equity holdings using live Bloomberg data
- Led department "Pass The Mic" meeting with 100+ attendees
- Updated IPO and SPAC details as new information arose

Canadian Armed Forces | Forces armées canadiennes Engineering Officer

December 2019 - June 2021 (1 year 7 months)

#### Toronto, Ontario, Canada

- Top 5 candidate on two-week army officer leadership course
- Planned and executed a mission effectively under immense stress
- Received verbal orders, analyzed information and presented new orders
- Used technical skills to confidently lead troops on a night navigation exercise
- Completed weapons handling test by performing tedious procedures
- Developed high attention to detail through routine morning inspections

## **Upper Grand District School Board**

Anti-Racism Advocate

November 2020 - January 2021 (3 months)

Guelph, Ontario, Canada

- Discussed racism with 200+ students at Elora Public School (primary, intermediate and junior)
- Developed two training videos for UGDSB educators upon request from Equity & Inclusion Lead
- Spoke with new UGDSB educators to improve anti-racism practices in schools

#### **TAPCOM**

Co-Founder

April 2020 - January 2021 (10 months)

Toronto, Ontario, Canada

- Achieved HTML/CSS proficiency in one month
- Led 25+ meetings focused on project management
- Developed four websites for local business owners
- Collaborated with journalists to write and publish two articles about TAPCOM
- Shopify theme development (Liquid) for e-commerce clients

# Education

University of Toronto

Bachelor of Applied Science - BASc, Industrial Engineering (2020 - 2024)

## National University of Singapore

NOC Internship Programme (Exchange), Entrepreneurship / Intellectual Property · (January 2022 - June 2022)

#### University of Toronto

Bachelor of Applied Science - BASc, Civil Engineering · (2018 - 2020)